Guide to the Peter E. Palmquist Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- General Research Files, 1822-2002; Series IV; 31.4 linear feet (75 boxes)
  - Carleton Watkins Research
    - Publications and Research about Watkins
      - Publications
        - "Wilderness and the Camera's Eye" Wilderness, Fall 1985, 1985 Fall (Box 122)
        - Pioneer Photography of the Great Basin (Box 122)
        - Carleton Watkins: Photographs from the Collection of the Park-McCullough House Association (Box 122)
        - "Carleton E. Watkins 1829-1915: Southwestern Photographer" Northlight, no. 1, 1977 (Box 122)
        - "Carleton Emmons Watkins" Mendocino Historical Review Newsletter, June 1982, 1982 June (Box 122)
        - Northern California 100 Years Ago (Box 122)
        - Exploiting the View: Photographs of Yosemite and Mariposa by Carleton Watkins (Box 122)
        - Carleton Watkins: Photographer (Box 122)
        - "California's 19th Century Master of the Grand View" Bookman's Weekly, February 3, 1992, 1992 February 3 (Box 122)
        - "On the Brink of Boom: The Early Photos of C. E. Watkins" California State Library Foundation Bulletin, October 1988, 1988 October (Box 122)
        - "Carleton E. Watkins: Master of the Grand View" The Rangefinder, June 1983, 1983 June (Box 122)
        - "Landscape as Legend: Carleton E. Watkins in Kern County" Landscape Journal, Spring 1992, 1992 Spring (Box 122)
        - "C. E. Watkins at Yosemite" Art in America, November-December 1978 (Box 122)
        - Carleton E. Watkins Photograph Collection, California State Library, Sacramento (Box 122)
        - The Early Pacific Coast Photographs of Carleton E. Watkins (Box 122)
        - "Portfolio: Carleton E. Watkins" American History Illustrated, April 1983, 1983 April (Box 122)
        - Watkins's Chronology Part No. 3 (Box 122)
        - Photographs of the Columbia River and Oregon (copy) (Box 122)
        - Taber Pacific Coast Tour Guide and Catalogue of Views (copy) (Box 122)
        - "The Photographist" Art in America, April 2000, 2000 April (Box 122)
        - "Toward a Definition of Process: The Yosemite Painting of Albert Bierstadt" (Master of Arts Thesis, Harvard), 1972 (Box 122)
        - The Ambrotype and Photographic Instructor (Copy) (Box 122)
        - Watkins Appendix A (Box 122)
        - Taber Pacific Coast Scenery (Copy) (Box 122)
    - Photocopies of Watkins Photographs
      Photocopies made by Palmquist of photographs by Watkins.
      - Mechanics' Fair (Box 123)
      - Portraits (Box 123)
      - Woodward's Gardens (Box 123)
      - USS Camanche (Box 123)
      - Street Cars (Box 123)
      - St. Ignatius College (Box 123)
      - San Francisco (Box 123)
      - Stereographs (Box 123)
    - Watkins Writings and Testimony
      Arranged sequentially by Palmquist's numbers.
      Typescript of writings and court testimony written by Watkins and transcribed by Palmquist.
      - Carleton E. Watkins: I-XXII (Box 124)
      - Carleton E. Watkins: XXIII-XLVI (Box 124)
      - Carleton E. Watkins: XLVI-LXXV (Box 124)
      - Carleton E. Watkins: LXXVI-CIX (Box 124)
      - Carleton E. Watkins: CX-CXXXII (Box 124)
    - Watkins Related Material
      Miscellaneous research material related to Watkins, including copies of photographs created by him, as well as a draft appendix for a work about Watkins.
      - Amon Carter Museum, "Carleton E. Watkins: Photographer of the American West," exhibition brochure, 1983-1984 (Box 125)
      - Copy photographs of Carleton E. Watkins photographs owned by Ron Bommarito, 1992 December (Box 125)
      - Copy photographs of a panorama from Russian Hill, San Francisco (Box 125)
      - Copy photographs of the mill at Big River before and after fire, from the collection of Eugene Compton (Box 125)
      - Copy photograph of "Spring Valley Water Works, No. 925, possible self-portrait of Watkins (Box 125)
      - Copy photographs of the Yosemite Valley (Box 125)
      - Illustrated report related to the consolidation of the Excelsior Canal Company, Blue Gravel Mining Company, and Nevada Reservoir Ditch Company in California, photocopy, circa 1873 (Box 125)
      - Notes related to Watkins and George Davidson (Box 125)
      - Photographs and postcards of the Malakoff Diggins in Nevada County, California, 1992-1995 (Box 125)
      - Unidentified author, "Carleton E. Watkins: A Historical View" (Box 125)
      - Unidentified author, Essay about Carleton Watkins (Box 125)
      - Watkins -- Appendix A (Box 125)
        Post-bound volume includes: I. The Watkins Family of Oneonta, New York; II. Court Depositions of Carleton Watkins in California Land Cases; III. Watkins's Daily Pocket Remembrancer for 1844; IV. Letters to, from, and about Carleton Watkins, 1865-1899.
  - Humboldt County
    Research files related to photography, as well as the history and geography of Humboldt County, California.
    Organized under eight headings: Sites in Humboldt County, Photography in Humboldt County, Newspaper Coverage of Events in Humboldt County and Del Norte County, Sanborn Fire Insurance Maps of Arcata, California, Motion Picture Theaters and Motion Picture Films in Humboldt County, Humboldt Arts Council, and General Research and Ephemera.
    - Sites in Humboldt County
      - Eureka (Box 126)
      - Fieldbrook (Box 126)
      - Loleta (Box 126)
    - Photography in Humboldt County
      Notes and clippings related to photography in Humboldt County, California.
      - Photographers of Humboldt County (Box 126)
      - "The old logging trucks," Daily Standard (Eureka, California ), 1894 December 19 (Box 126)
      - "The prospects are that Arcata will have a new photographic gallery soon," The Arcata Union, 1905 November 11 (Box 126)
      - Brizards 50th Anniversary coverage in The Arcata Union, 1913 July 3 (Box 126)
      - "California Press Association," The Arcata Union, 1916 May 25 (Box 126)
      - "Photographers Continue Code for this Area," Humboldt Standard ?, 1935 June 7 (Box 126)
      - "Redwood Country Album - Diamond Fruit Co.," The Times-Standard, 1976 December 27 (Box 126)
      - "Park Photo Sought," The Times-Standard ?, 1988 (Box 126)
      - Newspaper clippings about photography and Humboldt County, circa 1890-1900 (Box 126)
    - Newspaper Coverage of Events in Humboldt County and Del Norte County
      Negative overlays of newspaper and magazine coverage of events primarily in Humboldt County, as well as some events in Del Norte County, California, 1963-1964.
      - Humboldt Standard, Burglary ring, 1963 February 7; 2 folders (Box 126)
      - Christmas flood of 1964, 1964 December-1965 January; 5 folders (Box 126)
      - Tsunami in Crescent City, Del Norte County, 1964 March 28; 2 folders (Box 126)
    - Sanborn Fire Insurance Maps of Arcata, California
      Arranged with a key to the maps followed by the maps arranged chronologically.
      Photocopies of Sanborn Fire Insurance Maps of Arcata, California, 1889-1928, which are maps designed to assist fire insurance agents in determining the degree of hazard associated with a particular property. They show the size, shape, and construction of dwellings, commercial buildings, and factories, as well as fire walls, locations of windows and doors, sprinkler systems, and types of roofs. The maps also indicate widths and names of streets, property boundaries, building use, and house and block numbers.
      - Key (Box 127)
      - 1889 (Box 127)
      - 1900 (Box 127)
      - 1908 (Box 127)
      - 1919 (Box 127)
      - 1928 (Box 127)
    - Motion Picture Theaters and Motion Picture Films in Humboldt County
      Photographs and ephemera related to movie theaters and motion picture films in Humboldt County, California, as well as material related to an article about the movie Valley of the Giants (1927), and works by Tom E. Murray related to an exhibit at the Clarke Museum in Eureka, California, about films and theaters in Humboldt County.
      Organized under three headings: Photographs and Ephemera, Valley of the Giants, Works by Tom E. Murray
      - Photographs and Ephemera
        - Arcata Theater (Box 128)
        - Cain Rock, 1914 (Box 128)
          Photograph of a film crew at Cain Rock, Humboldt County, probably during the filming of Driving the Gold Spike (1914).
        - Empire Theater (Box 128)
        - Eureka Theater (Box 128)
        - Imperial Vaudeville (Box 128)
        - The Imperial (Box 128)
        - Ingomar Theater (Occidental Theater) (Box 128)
        - Loew's State Theater (Box 128)
        - Maribel Theater (Box 128)
        - Occidental Theater (Box 128)
        - The Orpheum Theater (Box 128)
        - Pastime Theater, 2 folders (Box 128)
        - Portola Theater (Box 128)
        - Rialto Theater, 2 folders (Box 128)
        - Russ Hall (Box 128)
        - State Theater (Box 128)
        - Sunset Drive-in Theater (Box 128)
        - Winema Theater, 2 folders (Box 128)
        - Unidentified theater (Box 128)
      - Valley of the Giants
        - Newspaper clipping, 1927 (Box 128)
        - Production photographs (Box 128)
        - Scott, Arden B."' Valley of the Giants ' Recalled," Humboldt Historian, 1974 March-April (Box 128)
        - Material related to a 1992 screening at the Minor Theater in Arcata (Box 128)
      - Works by Tom E. Murray
        - Murray, Tom E., Movie Theatres of Humboldt County: The First Century (Eureka, California: Clarke Museum), 1992 (Box 128)
        - Murray, Tom E. Movies Made in Humboldt County (Eureka, California: Clarke Museum), 1992 (Box 128)
    - Humboldt Arts Council
      Biographical/Historical note
      The Humboldt Arts Council based in the Morris Graves Museum of Art in Eureka, California, promotes the arts mainly by funding local artists, awarding prizes, and organizing events in Humboldt County, California.
      Correspondence with local artists, as well as color slides and photographic prints that document their work.
      - Alba, Benny (Box 129)
      - Albiani, Primo (Box 129)
      - Ambrosini, Armand (Box 129)
      - Ayron, Bill (Box 129)
      - Bennion, Chris (Box 129)
      - Bernstein, R. (Box 129)
      - Bibbs, Susheel (Box 129)
      - Bieniek, V. (Box 129)
      - Blakely, Dona (Box 129)
      - Boettcher, Frances (Box 129)
      - Boomer, Carol (Box 129)
      - Brent, Heather (Box 129)
      - Bucquet, George (Box 129)
      - Buehler, Stuart (Box 129)
      - Buehler, Teal (Box 129)
      - Burleson, Kathrin (Box 129)
      - Carey, Ellen (Box 129)
      - Coenen-Winee, Fiona (Box 129)
      - Costa, Art (Box 129)
      - Davis, Rebecca (Box 129)
      - Dell'Arte International School of Physical Theatre (Box 129)
      - Dhein, Christine (Box 129)
      - Dickinson, Peggy (Box 129)
      - DiConstanzo, Natalie (Box 129)
      - Dietl, Steve (Box 129)
      - Dismuke, Alan (Box 129)
      - Donald, Mary (Box 129)
      - Donvieve (Box 129)
      - Evans, Becky (Box 129)
      - Evenson, Judy (Box 129)
      - Farley, Brendon (Box 129)
      - Floersheimer, Stephen (Box 129)
      - Farnkel, David (Box 129)
      - Frye, Bob (Box 129)
      - Gallacher, Patrick J. (Box 129)
      - Gilbert and George (Box 129)
      - Golighty, Paula (Box 129)
      - Gray, Bryce (Box 129)
      - Gromt, Nina (Box 129)
      - Halkides, Dennis (Box 129)
      - Harris, Pat (Box 129)
      - Harstad, Katherine (Box 129)
      - Healy, Sandra (Box 129)
      - Hendrix, Ralphie (Box 129)
      - Hernandez, Veronica (Box 129)
      - Hibler, Starla (Box 129)
      - Higgins, Julie (Box 129)
      - High Fiber Designs (Box 129)
      - Hiller, Susan (Box 129)
      - Hooper, Cynthia A. (Box 129)
      - Humboldt Calypso Band (Box 129)
      - Jantz, Carol Louise (Box 129)
      - Jarvela, Ken (Box 129)
      - Jones, Ling Yen (Box 129)
      - Kalena, Richard (Box 129)
      - Katri, Joan (Box 129)
      - Kennedy, Bazi (Box 129)
      - Kramer, Mary Beth (Box 129)
      - Kulik, Zofia (Box 129)
      - Lagros, James (Box 129)
      - Lake, Carol (Box 129)
      - Landrum, Dale (Box 129)
      - Larson, Juanita (Box 129)
      - Larve, George (Box 129)
      - Lastel, Paul (Box 129)
      - Levitt, Catie (Box 129)
      - Lewis, Megan (Box 129)
      - Linitart, Anne (Box 129)
      - Lyttle, Lynn (Box 129)
      - Mabb, David (Box 129)
      - Madrone, Oceana (Box 129)
      - McCovey, Lena Reed (Box 129)
      - Mcdonough, Nancy (Box 129)
      - Milani, Richard (Box 129)
      - Mitchell, Linda (Box 129)
      - Mjurica, Uma (Box 129)
      - Monte, Lisa (Box 129)
      - Morace, Jake K. (Box 129)
      - Morales, Jeff (Box 129)
      - Nance, George (Box 129)
      - Neel, Susan (Box 129)
      - Norman, Leilani (Box 129)
      - Olsen, Marylin A. (Box 129)
      - Parish, Richard (Box 129)
      - Parker, Lynn (Box 129)
      - Parker, Stone (Box 129)
      - Peterson-Rav, Cheryl (Box 129)
      - LaPlantz, David (Box 129)
      - Price, L. K. (Box 129)
      - Radtke, Joyce (Box 129)
      - Reichek, Elaine (Box 129)
      - Reyes, Desiree Morgan (Box 129)
      - Reynolds, Yvonne M. (Box 129)
      - Ringgold, Faith (Box 129)
      - Roberts, Betsy (Box 129)
      - Roscoe-Bragg, Lee (Box 129)
      - Schneider, Keith (Box 129)
      - Schwab, Fred (Box 129)
      - Sisneros, Judy (Box 129)
      - Smith, David (Box 129)
      - Smith, Teda (Box 129)
      - Stafford, Carol (Box 129)
      - Stanley, Teresa (Box 129)
      - Sukup, Mary (Box 129)
      - Sweet, Dottie (Box 129)
      - Taaffe, Philip (Box 129)
      - Taylor, Janet (Box 129)
      - Tobyn, Nancy (Box 129)
      - Trabert, Eric L. (Box 129)
      - University of California, Los Angeles, Guitar Quartet (Box 129)
      - Vaisman, Meyer (Box 129)
      - Willis, Judy (Box 129)
      - Waters, Lisa Marie (Box 129)
      - Wolgemuth, Mark (Box 129)
      - Wool, Christopher (Box 129)
      - Zalewski, Thomas G. (Box 129)
    - General Research and Ephemera
      Files consisting of material, including clippings, business cards, and program ribbons, related to persons, businesses, and organizations in Humboldt County.
      - Babcock, George, a lecturer for the Independent Order of Good Templars (Box 130)
      - Bonstell, W. T. bookseller in Eureka (Box 130)
      - Bowman's Drug Store in Eureka (Box 130)
      - Broadside for a baseball game between the Humboldts and the F. J. Stibers at Kerfoot Grounds, probably in Ferndale, circa 1885-1890 (Box 130)
      - Coeur, Alexander, merchant in Freshwater, receipt with a price list for tobacco, circa 1887 (Box 130)
      - Depositions in the case of People v. Wah Yee, Police Court, Eureka, California, 1884 September 22 (Box 130)
      - E. Janssen & Co., hardware store in Eureka (Box 130)
      - Eklund, John, of McKinleyville, bank account with the Bank of Arcata (Box 130)
      - Elliott and Co., Map to Illustrate Wind Currents of the Pacific Coast (Box 130)
      - Evening School, Eureka (Box 130)
      - G. Boscow & Son, Arcata (Box 130)
      - Humboldt Manufacturing Company, Arcata (Box 130)
      - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, Anniversary Lodge, No. 85, program ribbon, 1882 April 26 (Box 130)
      - Knights of Pythias, North Star Lodge, No. 39, program ribbon, 1884 May 8 (Box 130)
      - Little Red Hen Service Station, Stone Lagoon (Box 130)
      - McKay, Mary, spiritualist in Eureka (Box 130)
      - McKellar, Dugald and Mary, Duties on land values in Scotland (Box 130)
      - Marriage Certificate for Mary Margarita Albanco and Andrew Ballinger (Box 130)
      - Mortgage deed from Jonathan Clark to Henry G. Gow for property in Eureka, 1882 July 5 (Box 130)
      - Mortgage deed from Henry G. Gow to John S. Connick for property in Eureka, 1883 August 17 (Box 130)
      - Taylor, Charles G., grocer in Eureka (Box 130)
      - Whitmore, Frank, of Arcata, a letter from an unidentified cousin staying at the Hotel Ramona in San Luis Obispo, California, 1892 February 19 (Box 130)
      - Pacific Coast Wood and Iron, 1893 (Box 130)
      - Weekly Humboldt Times, Broadside for a municipal election in Eureka, circa 1915 (Box 130)
  - California
    Organized under six headings: Photography in California, Stereoscopic Photography in California, Yosemite National Park, Calaveras Big Trees State Park, Journal of Isaac Tibbets Coffin, and California Gold Rush.
    Research files related to photography, as well as the history and geography of California.
    - Photography in California
      Organized under three headings: Indices and Directories, Copies of Sources, and Research Notes.
      Research files documenting photographers and photography throughout California.
      - Indices and Directories
        - General reference works on photographers active in California prior to 1900 (Box 131)
        - Index and listing of photographers active in California prior to 1900 (Box 131)
        - Photocopies of San Francisco business directories with photographer entries, 1856-1900 (Box 131)
      - Copies of Sources
        Organized chronologically.
        This material consists chiefly of copy photographs and photocopies of sources related to photography and photographers active in California.
        - "Collection of Curiosities," San Francisco Daily Herald, 1851 September 27 (Box 131)
        - "The Coast Survey," The San Francisco Herald, 1852 February 25 (Box 131)
        - "A Magnificent View of San Francisco," San Francisco Daily Herald, 1852 November 7 (Box 131)
        - "Photography in California," The American Journal of Photography, 1857 April 1 (Box 131)
        - Wells, William Vincent, "The Quicksilver Mines of New Almadan, California," Harper's New Monthly Magazine, 1863 June (Box 131)
        - "Wonders of Photography," Mariposa Gazette, 1863 October 10 (Box 131)
        - "Photographed on the corpses," San Jose Daily Evening Patriot, 1866 September 1 (Box 131)
        - Browne, J. C., "Dark Tents," The Philadelphia Photographer, 1868 March (Box 131)
        - "San Francisco Photography," Daily Alta California, 1871 October 31 (Box 131)
        - Hoffman and Graves, "Map: Bloomfield Hydraulic Mining Co.", 1872 (Box 131)
        - Rice & Baltzell, Official Map of Mendocino County, California, 1890 (Box 131)
        - Index to biographical sketches in Lewis Publishing Company, The Bay of San Francisco: The Metropolis of the Pacific Coast and Its Suburban Cities. A History (Chicago: Lewis Publishing Company), 1892 (Box 131)
        - "Picture Sharps," Stockton Daily Evening Record, 1896 March 18 (Box 131)
        - Frederick, M. C., "Whopping Grape Fruit," The Land of Sunshine, 1900 August (Box 131)
        - Hayne, Thomas, "Snapshots Tell Story of 1906 Earthquake," Los Angeles Times, 1980 January 13 (Box 131)
        - Stereographs of the San Francisco Earthquake from the collection of Peg (Box 131)
      - Research Notes
        - Alta California newspaper, notes, 1849-1851 (Box 131)
        - Burlingame-San Mateo Directory, 1931-1932 (Box 131)
        - Daguerreotypes (Box 131)
        - Hathaway, Pat, 2 folders (Box 131)
        - University of the Pacific, Locke-Hammond Family Papers (Box 131)
    - Stereoscopic Photography in California
      Organized under four headings: Stereograph Publishers and Distributors, Yosemite National Park, Collected Writings, and Stereographs in Collections.
      Material documenting stereoscopic photographers and publishers active in California. Louis Henry Smaus (1916-1990), a collector of stereoscopic formats, compiled much of this information about stereoscopic photography jointly with Palmquist.
      - Stereograph Publishers and Distributors
        - California stereographers, 1991, undated; 2 folders (Box 132)
        - H. C. White Co. (Box 132)
        - Sawyer's, Inc., and View-Master (Box 132)
        - Stereographs of Indians of North America (Box 132)
        - Truvue (Box 132)
      - Yosemite National Park
        Material collected by Smaus and Palmquist about stereoscopic photographers active in Yosemite National Park.
        - Bierstadt, Charles (Box 132)
        - Harris, W. (Box 132)
        - Pond, C. L. (Box 132)
        - Reilly, John James, 1984-1985; 6 folders (Box 132)
        - Soule, John Payson, 1979-1981 (Box 132)
        - Thomas Houseworth & Co., and Lawrence & Houseworth (Box 132)
        - Yosemite National Park Museum Collections, 1991 January-March; 2 folders (Box 132)
      - Collected Writings
        - McIntyre, Robert L., et al. "A Look at Stereo" (Box 132)
        - Osborn, C. B. "Stereograms on Postcards." Camera Craft, 1912 July (Box 132)
        - Treadwell, T. K. "Memo for those interested in restoration of faded stereo views.", 1987 September 13 (Box 132)
      - Stereographs in Collections
        Photocopies of stereographs depicting California in private collections and repositories.
        - Appollo, Ken, 1991 September (Box 132)
        - Crocker Art Museum, 1991 September (Box 132)
    - Yosemite National Park
      Organized under three headings: Articles by Louis H. Smaus, Persons and Companies, and James Mason Hutchings.
      Material, chiefly copy photographs, related to photographers, entrepreneurs, companies, and others in the Yosemite Valley and Yosemite National Park during the late nineteenth century and early twentieth century.
      - Articles by Louis H. Smaus
        - Smaus, Louis H., "Preliminary Yosemite Chronology: Artists, Photographers and Other key Figures and Events," typescript, 1986 December 27 (Box 133)
        - Smaus, Louis H., "The Artists & Photographers of Yosemite (1855-1935)," Yosemite, 1987 Winter (Box 133)
        - Smaus, Louis H., "Yosemite in Stereo," Yosemite, 1989 Summer (Box 133)
        - Smaus, Louis H., "Stereo Photographers and Publishers of Yosemite," typescript, 1989 December 5 (Box 133)
      - Persons and Companies
        - Bierstadt, Albert (Box 133)
        - Bierstadt, Charles (Box 133)
        - Boysen, J. T. (Box 133)
        - Cook, John Jay (Box 133)
        - Curtis, C. C. (Box 133)
        - Dusy, Frank (Box 133)
        - Fagersteen, Gustav (Box 133)
        - Fiske, George (Box 133)
        - Griffith and Griffith (Box 133)
        - Harris, W. (Box 133)
        - Hazeltine, M. M. (Box 133)
        - Houseworth, Thomas (Box 133)
        - Jackson, William Henry (Box 133)
        - Keystone View Company (Box 133)
        - Kilburn, B. W. (Box 133)
        - Littleton View Company (Box 133)
        - Melander, Clinton (Box 133)
        - Muybridge, Eadweard James (Box 133)
        - Plecker, D. A. (Box 133)
        - Pond, Charles L. (Box 133)
        - Reilly, J. J. (Box 133)
        - Roche, Thomas C., 2 folders (Box 133)
        - Savage, Charles R. (Box 133)
        - Scripture, J. C. (Box 133)
        - Todd, John A., 3 folders (Box 133)
        - Vroman, Adam Clark (Box 133)
        - Watkins, Carleton E. (Box 133)
        - Weed, Charles Leander (Box 133)
        - Young, John F. (Box 133)
        - Young, R. Y. (Box 133)
        - Notes (Box 133)
        - Copy photographs (Box 133)
        - Photocopies of articles, 13 folders (Box 133)
      - James Mason Hutchings
        Material related to James Mason Hutchings (1820-1902), an English American businessman and a principal promoter of Yosemite National Park.
        - Diary Transcriptions
          Typescript transcriptions of the manuscript diary by Gertrude "Cosie" Hutchings Mills
          - July 15-18, 1849 (Box 134)
          - 1855 (Box 134)
          - 1855, bound volume (Box 135)
        - Research Material
          - Volume of research material and notes (Box 136)
          - Palmquist: "Picturing the Elephant," draft, 2 folders (Box 137)
          - Illustrations from Hutchings' California Magazine, 2 folders (Box 137)
          - Biographical notes on James M. Hutchings, 3 folders (Box 137)
          - Hutchings material in the Yosemite Museum (Box 137)
          - Research notes, 5 folders (Box 137)